# Wesley J. Snyder

#### Summary:

Twenty years of customer service experience across the hospitality and gaming industries, including six years educating the young minds of the next generation. An educational background rooted in studying the human element that has yielded an AA, a BA and an MA. This path has bred a strong-willed, analytical, detail-oriented man of honor and integrity. I'd be perfect for a role as a Front-End Web Developer who either works closely with the client, meeting and exceeding their expectations, or with a team of programmers, collaborating and optimizing production.

## Objective:

To locate a Front-End Web Developer opportunity where I can my utilize my certified training, synthesized with my experience in academia and interpersonal communications, to fulfill the demands of client-side coding, as well as take a holistic approach to addressing and solving the needs of the client while maximizing output and efficiency for the company.

### Skills:

HTML GitHub Error-handling **CSS Express** Data Validation Authentication **JavaScript** Mongo Async JS Mongoose Authorization EJS Mongo Atlas Cookies Terminal Cloudinary Bootstrap Node **DOM** Heroku Git OOP

# Education:

May 2022 – Present React Full Course 2022

This course covers the essentials of the React JS Library including props, components, states, forms, and APIs.

May 2022 – Present JavaScript: The Advanced Concepts 2022

This course covers the foundations of JavaScript including types, closures, inheritance, modules, error handling, data structures and OOP.

Nov 2021 – May 2022 Web Development Bootcamp 2022

This course covered the basics of web development, from creating an appealing, functional UI/UX to setting up servers and databases with error handling and security

2015 – 2016 MA in Education from the University of Rediands	2015 - 2016	MA in Education from the University of Redlands
---	-------------	---

2011- 2013 BA in Philosophy from the University of California, San Diego

2008- 2010 AA from MiraCosta College

Work Experience:

January 2022 – Present Optic Design Pro

Co-owner/Web Developer/Editor

Started a Web Development business, specializing in website creation with Wordpress or JS, website maintenance, content

editing and creation

2020 – June 2022	Middle School ELA Teacher at Thurmont Middle School

2016 – 2020 High School ELA Teacher at Noli Indian School

2013 – 2016 Poker Supervisor and Dealer at Pechanga Resort and Casino Server and Bartender at a variety of 5-star resorts and restaurants

2001 – 2004 Customer Service at various establishments